TY BAYN SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Personal Info

Location: Layton, UT

Phone: (801) 917-7265

Email: tylermbayn@gmail.com

LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/ty-bayn

GitHub:

Website:

Languages



Docker	Proficient
Docker	
	Proficient
SQLAlchemy	
	Proficient
Kafka / Event Streaming	
	Proficient
Kubernetes	
	Novice
AWS / S3	
	Novice
	NOVICE
Skills	

FastAPI

Software Development

Collaborative Programming

Agile / Scrum

Proficient

Expert

Proficient

Experienced Software Engineer and Data Engineer with a demonstrated history of developing complex and enterprise level software. Skilled in Python, C#, SQL, and web languages. Utilizes many technologies including Docker and is experienced in event driven architecture. Has worked in many different programming roles and has developed a wide range of skills as a software engineer, data engineer, web developer, and data analyst.

Education

Southern Utah University

BS, Computer Science Utah

Aug 2018 Summa Cum Laude

- Apr 2020 Grade-Point Average: 4.0/4.0

Snow College

Utah

AS, Computer Science

Aug 2015 Summa Cum Laude - Apr 2018

Grade-Point Average: 3.93/4.0

Experience

What If Media Group











Mar 2024 - Present

Data Engineer III

- Work with multiple teams to create accurate and efficient data pipelines using Snowflake, Databricks, and Apache Airflow
- Identify, design, and implement internal process improvements, including automating manual processes and optimizing data delivery

1010data (Part of SymphonyAI)









Mar 2023 - Feb 2024

Lead Software Development Engineer

- Lead a team in developing and implementing streaming and event-based software using Apache Kafka
- Work with multiple teams to streamline, automate, and centralize development practices and code resources
- Develop tools and resources for use in data pipeline by Data Engineers

Full-time

Data Engineer III

May 2022

Develop and maintain ETL data pipelines using Apache Airflow

- Mar 2023

• Develop software to streamline, automate, and centralize development practices and code resources

Full-time

Data Engineer I

Nov 2021 - May 2022

• Develop and maintain ETL data pipelines using Apache Airflow

• Work with multiple teams to streamline, automate, and centralize development practices and code resources

PhoneSoap





Full-time Nov 2020 - Oct 2021

Business Intelligence Engineer

- Developed software to clean and load data from various sources
- Created visualizations and reports to assist in making data-supported business decisions

Contract Jul 2020 - Oct 2020

Business Intelligence Consultant

• Used various ETL technologies to collect data from various ad and eCommerce sources and load them into a data warehouse for centralized reporting

GuardSight, Inc.



Intern

Jan 2020 - Apr 2020

Software Engineer / Data Analyst

• Developed a data analytics tool and plotting engine in Python3 to visualize historic cybersecurity events, show anomalies in historic data, and predict/detect anomalies in live data